Jahnavi Prasad

Toronto, ON +1 782 882 6286 iprasad@dal.ca linkedin.com/in/jahnaviprasad

Graduating Master's student with 3 years of experience in a fast-paced hyper-growth startup environment seeking a position in your esteemed organization to contribute my skills to a team that values excellence.

EDUCATION

Dalhousie University Halifax, Canada Master of Applied Computer Science Sep 2023 - Dec 2024

L P University Jalandhar, India Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science and Engineering (Honors.) Aug 2018 - July 2022

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

WATI by Clare AI Fully Remote Solutions Engineer Oct 2022 - Dec 2024

- Developed SaaS integrations between WATI product and customer environments using REST APIs
- Led and scaled the Solutions Team from 1 to 5 members, boosting client solutioning and integration capabilities by 400% within 18 months.
- Onboarded 350+ small-to-medium businesses (SMBs) on WhatsApp Business API, driving the adoption of AI-powered conversational bots on WhatsApp.
- Served as primary liaison for the sales team, addressing all information security inquiries from prospects contributing to \$800,000 in closed deals.

Key Skills: Problem solving, Data Integration, REST APIs, Infosec, Consulting, Conversational AI

Whatfix Bangalore, India Solutions Engineer Jan 2022 - Sep 2022 Apr 2021 - Dec 2021

Solutions Engineer Intern

- Gathered requirements from enterprise customers, and designed, built, and tested custom solutions using Javascript and REST APIs to drive digital adoption.
- Designed and implemented RESTful APIs using AWS DynamoDB, Lambda, and API Gateway, allowing seamless integration with third-party services and increasing data exchange efficiency by 50%.
- Contributed to key Whatfix Analytics features released in Q2 & Q3 2022.
- Subject matter expert in integrating Whatfix products with enterprise Business Intelligence tools.

Key Skills: AWS, Application testing, Integrations, REST APIs, Workflow Automation, Debugging.

Key Achievements: 2 Spot Awards and 25+ appreciations. Rescued 7 critical accounts from churn.

PROJECTS

ResumeLab.tech Winter 2024

A web application that allows users to build and improve resumes using AI-powered suggestions. A solo project was developed as part of the Advanced Topics in Cloud Computing course in the Winter 2024 term. Built using HTML, CSS, JS, AWS Lambda, Step functions, AWS SNS, and AWS API Gateway. Hosted on GitHub Pages. Powered by: Open AI's gpt-3.5-turbo LLM model. Accessible at: https://jahnavi-prasad.github.io/resumelab/

Portfolio Websites Fall 2023

Built two personal portfolio websites to showcase my work, interests, and accomplishments. Built using HTML, CSS, and JS. Incorporated JavaScript functionalities to enhance interactivity, such as smooth scrolling and dynamic animations. Implemented search engine optimization (SEO) techniques. Hosted on GitHub Pages. Accessible at www.iahnaviprasad.com. A terminal-themed version can be accessed at javpii.me

Car Prediction for Road Trip

Fall 2021

Web App that predicts the most suitable car for a trip based on user inputs like the trip distance, gas prices, and budget. Created to showcase my understanding of Exploratory Data Analysis. Built using R Language, RStudio, and shinyapps. Can be accessed at <u>jahnaviprasad.shinyapps.io/Car-for-road-trip</u>

Sorting Visualizer Winter 2024

A website to visualize the inner workings of Bubble, Selection, Insertion, Merge, Quick, and Heap sorting algorithms. Built using HTML, CSS, and JS. Hosted on GitHub pages. Accessible at: jahnavi-prasad.github.io/SortingVisualizer

Culture Connect Winter 2024

A Figma design for a web application intended to help people assimilate into new cultures. Designed as part of the Technology Innovation course in the Winter 2024 term. Access at: https://figmashort.link/GkcARe

CERTIFICATIONS

- Six Sigma White Belt Link
- IBM Data Science Professional Certificate Link
- IBM Advanced Data Science Specialization Link
- Big Data Specialization from UC San Diego <u>Link</u>
- Oracle Cloud 2024 Generative AI Certified Professional Link
- Deep Learning Specialization by DeepLearning.AI Link
- Google IT Support Professional Certificate Link
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals, AI Fundamentals, Data Fundamentals Link
- AWS Fundamentals Link

ACHIEVEMENTS/AWARDS

• Written and Published a book (Ancient War Drama) titled Gaul, Walls, and Alesia

Fall 2021

• Trained 4400+ students across 107 countries with my Python courses on Udemy

Winter 2024

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

Programming Languages: C/C++, Python, Java, JavaScript, R Language, and Bash

Frontend: HTML, CSS, React

Data Capture: REST APIs, Webhooks

Data Query: SQL, NoSQL

Data Storage: Snowflake, AWS S3, AWS Redshift

Data Analysis: PowerBI, Looker, Tableau, Google Analytics

Cloud Platforms: AWS, Azure, and GCP

Other Tools: Github, JIRA, Confluence, Postman, MS Office Suite, Figma, Zapier, Zendesk, and Zoho Suite Soft Skills: Communication, Problem-solving, Team Management, Customer Communication, Consulting